LEAH CARDOZ

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack software engineer with a knack for eye-catching, user-friendly web design. With a decade of experience supporting C-level executives in the live music industry, I excel in delivering optimal results with high emotional intelligence and professionalism in fast-paced environments. Motivated, curious, and eager to kickstart my career in tech, I look forward to adapting and expanding my skill set at a workplace that values innovation and collaboration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | ReactJS | HTML | CSS | Redux | Ruby on Rails | SQLite | PostgreSQL | Material UI | Semantic UI | Git | GitHub | RESTful APIs | VS Code | Vite | npm | Figma | Canva | Postman | Netlify

TECHNICAL APPLICATIONS

Gig Prints - GitHub | Demo

A hub for touring bands and poster designers to discover each other and connect to create concert posters together.

- Utilized a React frontend and Rails backend to respectively facilitate and harness CRUD actions for three models.
- Implemented authentication and authorization with a secure login/logout using password encryption and sessions.
- Pioneered an interactive frontend complete with react-router client-side routes and uniformly styled with Semantic UI.
- Compiled extensive seed data for the models into a custom built API utilizing foreign keys for the joiner model.

Engine-Ear. - GitHub | Demo

A social media app solely for software engineers to connect, network, and post content about anything coding-related.

- Created a user-friendly React interface employing Ruby on Rails for authenticated backend capabilities.
- Utilized six models via ActiveRecord including a self join table with alias ids for the user-to-user relationship.
- Strengthened signup and login security by using hashing, salting, and bcrypt to protect user data.

The Archive - GitHub (Frontend) | GitHub (Backend) | Demo

An application where users can showcase and submit their favorite screenprint artists and their prints.

- Architected a full stack application from the ground up, utilizing React for frontend and Ruby Sinatra API for backend.
- Engineered RESTful Routing by leveraging ActiveRecord associations to incorporate methods into controllers.
- Developed an API from scratch with full CRUD routing capabilities for two interactive models.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

City Winery International

New York, NY

Executive Assistant to CEO/Founder

05/2021 - 09/2022

- Efficiently streamlined the CEO's workflow by organizing schedules, owning projects, managing inboxes, shadow-writing emails, collaborating with cross-functional teams, and giving tours to investors and the press.
- Advanced the company's growth by conducting market research for location expansion, authoring and editing board decks for investor meetings, and fostering partnerships with local businesses on behalf of the CEO.
- Independently spearheaded large-scale events –including yearly management off-site conferences and numerous benefit galas– sourcing event spaces, arranging travel and hotel accommodations, and planning menus.

High Road Touring

Sausalito, CA 06/2015 - 07/2018

Artist Agent Assistant

• Convened with the CEO and a team of agents to effectively book concert tours for over 300 artists in America.

- Supervised the Contracts and Earnings Departments, vetting all signed contracts, immigration and insurance documents, and calculating and assuring accurate yearly earnings for all touring artists.
- Managed the administrative department by screening calls, organizing meetings, and training all new hires.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Full Stack Software Engineering Program

10/2022 - 01/2023

University of California, Berkeley – Walter A. Haas School of Business

Berkeley, CA 08/2011 - 05/2015